Maria Alejandra Macias

Dedicated Full Stack developer with 3 years of experience using Angular, React.js and Vue.js frameworks as well as advanced database concepts with a wide range of knowledge in programming utilities and languages such as Java, Javascript, Typescript and C#. Skilled in adapting to new situations and challenges to best enhance the problem solving process. Fluent in English and Spanish and accustomed to working with cross-cultural, global teams.

50 Ann O'Reilly Rd M2J 0C9, Toronto, ON, CA (+1) 437 366 0343 m.maciasprado@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAM Sports, Toronto, Canada

Software Engineer

APRIL 2023 - Current

- Developed and modified the companies web application using React.js framework, and Express.js platform along with MySQL database.
- Wrote structured, readable code with best practices for each language.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery with an agile team.
- Gathered and defined requirements and acceptance criteria to develop clear specification for new features and project plans.

Uruit, Bogotá, Colombia

Full Stack Developer

APRIL 2021 - MARCH 2023

- Improved web page performance 68% for desktop and 45% for mobile view using React.js and Gatsby.js framework.
- Wrote structured, tested and readable code with best practices for each language.
- Developed 15+ new application features and services for high scale application
- Participated in weekly code review sessions to ensure quality and efficiency.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery with an agile team.
- Gathered and defined requirements and acceptance criteria to develop clear specification for new features and project plans.

SKILLS

- Critical thinking.
- Time management.
- Avid learner.
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub.
- Scripting Languages: PHP, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#.
- React , Angular, Vue
- SQL.
- Front-end skills: HTML, CSS, SCSS.
- Back-end and Database skills.
- Responsive mobile web design.

EDUCATION

Centennial College

Toronto, ON, Canada 2023-2024

CURRENT

Advanced Diploma: Software Engineering Technology

Nueva Granada Military University

Bogotá, Colombia

2015-2020

Bachelor of Mechatronics Engineering

University of Ontario Institute of Technology

Oshawa, ON, Canada

Summer 2019

Summer Course: Special Topics in Information Technology

Kloustr, Bogotá, Colombia

Junior Software Developer

MARCH 2020 - APRIL 2021

- Developed and modified 5+ front-end and back-end applications for web e-commerces using Angular framework and mongoDB platform.
- Developed 5+ new application features and services for high scale applications.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Carried out day to day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Served clients and followed outlined steps for customer service.